<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MatApp2</string>

    <string name="checkout_app_name">GetSetChalo</string>
    <string name="checkout_checkout">Checkout</string>
    <string name="checkout_proceed_confirm">Proceed to confirm booking</string>
    <string name="checkout_proceed_pay_now">Proceed to Pay Now</string>
    <string name="checkout_pay_later">I\'ll pay later</string>
    <string name="checkout_booking_reserved">BOOKING RESERVED!</string>
    <string name="checkout_confirm_pay">Confirm &amp; Pay</string>
    <string name="checkout_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="checkout_done">Done</string>
    <string name="checkout_my_profile">My Profile</string>
    <string name="checkout_attach_aadhar">📎  Upload Aadhar (PDF/Image)</string>
    <string name="checkout_attach_pdf">📄  Upload PDF</string>
    <string name="checkout_full_name_hint">Riya Sharma</string>
    <string name="checkout_age_hint">28</string>
    <string name="checkout_contact_hint">+91 98765 43210</string>
    <string name="checkout_email_hint">riya@email.com</string>
    <string name="checkout_aadhar_hint">XXXX XXXX XXXX</string>
    <string name="checkout_guest2_name_hint">Arjun Sharma</string>
    <string name="checkout_guest2_age_hint">30</string>
    <string name="checkout_guest2_contact_hint">+91 91234 56789</string>
    <string name="checkout_upi_hint">yourname@upi</string>
    <string name="tourist_app_name">Tourist Packages</string>
    <string name="mat_app_name">MAT_PROJECT</string>
    <string name="ta_app_name">Tourism app</string>


    <!-- ==================== td_ (TouristDestinations) ==================== -->
    <string name="td_app_name">TouristDestinations</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ TAJ MAHAL ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Taj Mahal&lt;/b&gt; is an ivory-white marble mausoleum on the southern bank of the Yamuna river. Commissioned in &lt;b&gt;1631&lt;/b&gt; by Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan in memory of his beloved wife Mumtaz Mahal, it stands as one of the world\'s most celebrated expressions of eternal love. Over &lt;b&gt;20,000 artisans&lt;/b&gt; from across the globe spent 22 years bringing this vision to life \u2014 a monument that transcends time.</string>
        <string name="td_tip_time_title">Best Time to Visit</string>
        <string name="td_tip_time_desc">Arrive at sunrise (6\u20137 AM) for the most magical golden light and minimal crowds. The Taj Mahal glows a soft amber at dawn.</string>
        <string name="td_tip_season_title">Ideal Season</string>
        <string name="td_tip_season_desc">October to March offers pleasant weather. Avoid May\u2013June as temperatures can exceed 45\u00b0C. The monsoon (July\u2013Sept) brings lush greenery.</string>
        <string name="td_tip_photo_title">Photography Tip</string>
        <string name="td_tip_photo_desc">Head to Mehtab Bagh across the Yamuna River for a stunning rear view. Use the reflecting pool near the main gate for iconic symmetrical shots.</string>
        <string name="td_tip_wear_title">What to Wear</string>
        <string name="td_tip_wear_desc">Wear shoe covers (provided free) or slip-on shoes \u2014 footwear must be removed near the main mausoleum. Modest clothing is recommended.</string>
        <string name="td_tip_tickets_title">Entry &amp; Tickets</string>
        <string name="td_tip_tickets_desc">Book tickets online via ASI website to skip queues. Foreign nationals pay \u20b91100; Indian nationals pay \u20b950. Entry restricted on Fridays.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ AGRA FORT ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_agra_fort_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Agra Fort&lt;/b&gt; is a colossal red sandstone fortress on the banks of the Yamuna River and a &lt;b&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/b&gt; since 1983. Originally built by &lt;b&gt;Emperor Akbar&lt;/b&gt; in 1565 and later expanded by his grandson Shah Jahan, this formidable citadel served as the main residence of the Mughal emperors. From its towers, Shah Jahan spent his final years gazing at the Taj Mahal \u2014 a poignant testament to his undying love.</string>
        <string name="td_agra_fort_tip_time_desc">Visit early morning (7\u20139 AM) for cooler temperatures and softer light on the red sandstone walls. Fewer crowds before 10 AM make exploration more peaceful.</string>
        <string name="td_agra_fort_tip_season_desc">October to February is the best time. The fort glows beautifully in winter sun. Avoid peak summer (April\u2013June); temperatures can soar above 45\u00b0C.</string>
        <string name="td_agra_fort_tip_photo_desc">Capture the Taj Mahal framed through the arched windows of the Musamman Burj tower \u2014 a truly iconic and moody composition enjoyed by few.</string>
        <string name="td_agra_fort_tip_wear_desc">Wear comfortable walking shoes as there is significant ground to cover inside. Carry water and sunscreen especially during warmer months.</string>
        <string name="td_agra_fort_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is \u20b940 for Indian nationals and \u20b9600 for foreign nationals. Tickets available at the gate or online via the ASI portal.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ TOMB OF AKBAR ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_tomb_akbar_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Tomb of Akbar the Great&lt;/b&gt; stands majestically in Sikandra on the outskirts of Agra. Begun by &lt;b&gt;Akbar himself&lt;/b&gt; and completed by his son Jahangir in &lt;b&gt;1613 AD&lt;/b&gt;, this magnificent mausoleum blends Hindu, Islamic, Buddhist, and Christian architectural elements \u2014 a reflection of Akbar\'s inclusive secular vision. Surrounded by lush Mughal gardens roaming freely with deer, it offers a serene escape from the city.</string>
        <string name="td_tomb_akbar_tip_time_desc">Early morning (7\u20139 AM) is ideal when the gardens are dewy and the light is soft. Spotted deer are most active at this time and create a magical atmosphere.</string>
        <string name="td_tomb_akbar_tip_season_desc">November to February provides the most comfortable weather for exploring. The garden surrounding the tomb is particularly beautiful in winter.</string>
        <string name="td_tomb_akbar_tip_photo_desc">The long axial pathway leading to the main gate makes for a stunning symmetrical shot. Zoom into the intricate white marble inlay on the red sandstone facade.</string>
        <string name="td_tomb_akbar_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is \u20b930 for Indian nationals and \u20b9310 for foreign nationals. The site is open from sunrise to sunset on all days of the week.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ ITMAD-UD-DAULA ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_itmad_about_text">Known as the &lt;b&gt;\'Baby Taj\'&lt;/b&gt;, Itmad-ud-Daula is widely considered a forerunner of the Taj Mahal. This exquisite jewel-box tomb was built by &lt;b&gt;Empress Nur Jahan&lt;/b&gt; between 1622\u20131628 AD in memory of her father Mirza Ghiyas Beg. The first Mughal structure built &lt;b&gt;entirely of white marble&lt;/b&gt; with intricate pietra dura (stone inlay) work, it inspired the artistic perfection later achieved in the Taj Mahal and remains a milestone in Mughal architecture.</string>
        <string name="td_itmad_tip_time_desc">Visit in the early morning when the marble gleams in the golden light. The lattice screen windows cast beautiful geometric shadows inside the tomb chamber.</string>
        <string name="td_itmad_tip_season_desc">October to March is perfect. The intimate scale of the monument makes it enjoyable year-round, but winter mornings are especially magical.</string>
        <string name="td_itmad_tip_photo_desc">Stand at the garden entrance for a full reflection shot in the water channel. The ornate pietra dura inlay on walls makes for extraordinary close-up photography.</string>
        <string name="td_itmad_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is \u20b920 for Indian nationals and \u20b9210 for foreign nationals. Closed on Fridays. Easy to combine with a Taj Mahal visit as both are nearby.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ SHAHI JAMA MASJID ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_jama_masjid_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Shahi Jama Masjid&lt;/b&gt; of Agra is one of the finest examples of Mughal mosque architecture, commissioned by &lt;b&gt;Emperor Shah Jahan&lt;/b&gt; and completed in &lt;b&gt;1648 AD&lt;/b&gt;. Dedicated to his daughter Jahanara Begum, this grand mosque features three magnificent marble domes and is built entirely of red sandstone with white marble accents. It can accommodate over &lt;b&gt;10,000 worshippers&lt;/b&gt; and remains an active place of worship and a symbol of Mughal grandeur in Agra.</string>
        <string name="td_jama_masjid_tip_time_desc">Visit between prayers (outside Fajr, Dhuhr, Asr, Maghrib, Isha times) for the most relaxed exploration. Friday congregational prayers create a deeply atmospheric experience.</string>
        <string name="td_jama_masjid_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal. The courtyard is fully open and the red sandstone glows warmly in winter sunlight. Ramadan evenings are especially vibrant with local culture.</string>
        <string name="td_jama_masjid_tip_wear_desc">Modest dress is mandatory \u2014 shoulders and knees must be covered. Women must cover their heads. Shoes must be removed before entering the prayer hall. Scarves are often available at the entrance.</string>
        <string name="td_jama_masjid_tip_photo_desc">Climb the steps leading to the courtyard for a wide-angle view of all three domes together. The symmetry and scale of the courtyard at dusk creates a spectacular photograph.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ HAWA MAHAL ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_hawa_mahal_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Hawa Mahal&lt;/b&gt; (Palace of Winds) is one of Jaipur&#8217;s most iconic landmarks &#8212; a stunning five-storey pyramidal facade of &lt;b&gt;953 small latticed windows (jharokhas)&lt;/b&gt; built from rose-pink sandstone. Commissioned in &lt;b&gt;1799 AD&lt;/b&gt; by Maharaja Sawai Pratap Singh, it was designed so royal ladies could observe street festivals while remaining unseen. The constant airflow through its honeycomb latticework keeps the interior cool even in peak summer &#8212; a marvel of Rajput ingenuity and elegance.</string>
        <string name="td_hawa_mahal_tip_time_desc">Visit early morning (8&#8211;10 AM) to catch the sun illuminating the pink facade from the east &#8212; it creates a breathtaking golden-rose glow. Evenings offer a magical silhouette view.</string>
        <string name="td_hawa_mahal_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal. The Pink City is vibrant in winter. The Hawa Mahal lit up during Diwali and festivals is especially spectacular &#8212; avoid peak summer above 42&#176;C.</string>
        <string name="td_hawa_mahal_tip_photo_desc">Cross the road to the Wind View Caf&#233; (rooftop) for the best full-facade shot. At street level, frame the palace between the bazaar stalls for a quintessential Jaipur composition.</string>
        <string name="td_hawa_mahal_tip_wear_desc">Comfortable sandals are ideal as you will climb numerous narrow interior staircases. Dress modestly as this is a royal heritage site &#8212; light cotton suits the warm climate best.</string>
        <string name="td_hawa_mahal_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;50 for Indian nationals and &#8377;200 for foreign nationals. The site includes access to the Royal Chambers Exhibition. Open daily 9 AM &#8211; 5 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ JANTAR MANTAR ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_jantar_mantar_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Jantar Mantar Jaipur&lt;/b&gt; is the largest and best-preserved of the five astronomical observatories built by &lt;b&gt;Maharaja Jai Singh II&lt;/b&gt; between 1724&#8211;1735. A &lt;b&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/b&gt; since 2010, it contains 19 major astronomical instruments including the world&#8217;s largest stone sundial &#8212; the &lt;b&gt;Samrat Yantra&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; which can measure time to an accuracy of 2 seconds. These monumental masonry instruments track celestial coordinates, predict eclipses, and gauge solar positions with remarkable precision.</string>
        <string name="td_jantar_mantar_tip_time_desc">Visit between 10 AM and 2 PM when a guide is available and the sundials cast their most readable shadows. Midday light creates dramatic geometric shadows across the instruments.</string>
        <string name="td_jantar_mantar_tip_season_desc">October to February is the best time. Sunrise visits let you witness the astronomical instruments being used in their purest context &#8212; tracking the first light of day.</string>
        <string name="td_jantar_mantar_tip_photo_desc">Climb the Samrat Yantra staircase for aerial shots of all 19 instruments below. The geometric abstractions of the Ram Yantra circles create extraordinary compositions.</string>
        <string name="td_jantar_mantar_tip_wear_desc">Comfortable walking shoes are essential &#8212; you will climb steep staircases on the sundial. Carry water and sunscreen; the open-air observatory offers minimal shade.</string>
        <string name="td_jantar_mantar_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;50 for Indian nationals and &#8377;200 for foreign nationals. Guided tours are available in English and Hindi for an additional &#8377;200. Open 9 AM &#8211; 4:30 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ CITY PALACE ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_city_palace_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;City Palace Jaipur&lt;/b&gt; is a magnificent complex built between &lt;b&gt;1729&#8211;1732 AD&lt;/b&gt; by Maharaja Sawai Jai Singh II as the royal seat of the Jaipur royal family. A stunning fusion of &lt;b&gt;Rajput, Mughal and European architecture&lt;/b&gt;, the palace complex includes the Chandra Mahal, Mubarak Mahal, Diwan-i-Khas, and seven-storey Chandra Mahal still occupied by the royal family. Home to the City Palace Museum with priceless Rajput treasures, the palace represents the cultural zenith of Rajputana refinement and grandeur.</string>
        <string name="td_city_palace_tip_time_desc">Visit early morning (9&#8211;11 AM) when the interiors are cool and light streams through the ornate archways. The Peacock Gate is magnificently lit in the morning sun.</string>
        <string name="td_city_palace_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal. The palace hosts special events and cultural performances during Diwali, Holi, and Gangaur festival that offer a rare glimpse into living royal tradition.</string>
        <string name="td_city_palace_tip_photo_desc">The Peacock Gate (Mor Gate) in Pritam Niwas Chowk is the most photographed spot &#8212; arrive early before tour groups. The courtyard fountain creates beautiful symmetrical reflections.</string>
        <string name="td_city_palace_tip_wear_desc">Smart casual dress is expected at this active royal residence. Remove shoes before entering inner sanctuaries. Photography is restricted in certain inner chambers of the royal residence.</string>
        <string name="td_city_palace_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;200 for Indian nationals and &#8377;700 for foreign nationals. The Royal Grandeur ticket (&#8377;2,500) includes royal gallery access. Open daily 9:30 AM &#8211; 5 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ JAL MAHAL ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_jal_mahal_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Jal Mahal&lt;/b&gt; (Water Palace) is a dreamlike &lt;b&gt;five-storey red sandstone palace&lt;/b&gt; that appears to float in the middle of Man Sagar Lake, Jaipur. Built in &lt;b&gt;1799 AD&lt;/b&gt; and restored by Maharaja Madho Singh I, four of its five storeys are submerged beneath the serene lake. The palace blends &lt;b&gt;Rajput and Mughal architectural styles&lt;/b&gt; and is surrounded by a bird sanctuary home to thousands of migratory birds including flamingos. The palace itself is closed to visitors but the lakeside promenade offers breathtaking views and sunset experiences.</string>
        <string name="td_jal_mahal_tip_time_desc">Sunrise and sunset are the magical hours &#8212; the palace reflects perfectly in the still lake water and the light turns the sandstone into shades of amber and rose gold.</string>
        <string name="td_jal_mahal_tip_season_desc">October to March is best. The lake fills up during monsoon (July&#8211;Sept) which is spectacular but the promenade can be muddy. Winter mornings bring flamingos and migratory birds.</string>
        <string name="td_jal_mahal_tip_photo_desc">The lakeside promenade offers the best long-lens shots of the palace against the Aravalli Hills. Use a wide-angle lens at sunset for the reflection shot; a tripod helps for longer exposures.</string>
        <string name="td_jal_mahal_tip_wear_desc">The lakeside promenade is paved &#8212; comfortable footwear works well. The area can be windy; keep valuables secure. Avoid feeding lake birds as it disturbs the ecosystem.</string>
        <string name="td_jal_mahal_tip_tickets_desc">The lakeside promenade and exterior views are free to enjoy. Boat rides on Man Sagar Lake are available for &#8377;50&#8211;&#8377;100. The palace interior remains restricted for conservation.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ ALBERT HALL MUSEUM ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_albert_hall_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Albert Hall Museum&lt;/b&gt; is Rajasthan&#8217;s oldest museum, housed in a spectacular &lt;b&gt;Indo-Saracenic building&lt;/b&gt; constructed between 1876&#8211;1887. Named after King Edward VII (then Prince of Wales, Prince Albert), it was designed by &lt;b&gt;Sir Samuel Swinton Jacob&lt;/b&gt; and opened to the public in 1887. The museum houses &lt;b&gt;over 16,000 artefacts&lt;/b&gt; including Egyptian mummies, Rajasthani miniature paintings, ivory works, carpets, sculptures, and historical weapons &#8212; a priceless archive of Rajputana civilization and global antiquities.</string>
        <string name="td_albert_hall_tip_time_desc">Visit at dusk (6&#8211;9 PM) when the museum is beautifully illuminated and open for evening hours. The golden lights on the ivory facade create a spectacular atmosphere loved by photographers.</string>
        <string name="td_albert_hall_tip_season_desc">Open year-round, but October to February is best for exploring the Ram Niwas Garden surrounding the museum. Winter evenings when the building is lit are especially memorable.</string>
        <string name="td_albert_hall_tip_photo_desc">The front lawn fountain and the illuminated facade at night create a magnificent composition. Inside, the Egyptian mummy gallery and Central Hall dome interior are extraordinary photographic subjects.</string>
        <string name="td_albert_hall_tip_wear_desc">Casual comfortable clothing works well. The museum is fully air-conditioned inside &#8212; carry a light layer. Photography is allowed in most sections; a permit (&#8377;50) is required for tripods.</string>
        <string name="td_albert_hall_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;40 for Indian nationals and &#8377;300 for foreign nationals. Open Sat&#8211;Thu 9 AM&#8211;5 PM and 7&#8211;10 PM; closed Fridays. Evening light show is free for ticket holders.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ JAIGARH FORT ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_jaigarh_fort_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Jaigarh Fort&lt;/b&gt; (&#8216;Fort of Victory&#8217;) crowns the &#8216;Eagle Hill&#8217; (Cheel ka Teela) above Amber Fort, serving as the Amber Palace&#8217;s military protector. Built by &lt;b&gt;Maharaja Jai Singh II in 1726&lt;/b&gt;, this formidable fortress houses the world&#8217;s &lt;b&gt;largest wheeled cannon &#8212; the Jaiv&#257;na&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; which was never fired in battle. Connected to Amber Fort by an underground tunnel, Jaigarh protected the royal treasury and commanded panoramic views over the entire Dhundhar region &#8212; a testament to Rajput military architecture at its most formidable.</string>
        <string name="td_jaigarh_fort_tip_time_desc">Visit in the morning (9&#8211;11 AM) for the best panoramic views of Amber Fort and the Maota Lake below before haze builds. The Jaivan cannon is most impressive in early light.</string>
        <string name="td_jaigarh_fort_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal for clear panoramic vistas. Monsoon brings lush green Aravalli Hills which are stunning &#8212; though the climb can be slippery. Avoid midday in summer.</string>
        <string name="td_jaigarh_fort_tip_photo_desc">Climb to the Diya Burj watchtower for a 360&#176; panorama of Amber, Nahargarh, and the pink city below. The Jaivan cannon barrel makes for a dramatic framing element in wide shots.</string>
        <string name="td_jaigarh_fort_tip_wear_desc">Sturdy walking shoes are essential &#8212; the fort involves significant climbing on uneven stone paths. Carry water as there are limited refreshments inside. A hat is strongly advised.</string>
        <string name="td_jaigarh_fort_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;35 for Indian nationals and &#8377;85 for foreign nationals. Jeeps from Amber Fort gate are available for &#8377;100 per person. Open daily 9 AM &#8211; 4:30 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ AMBER PALACE ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_amber_palace_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Amber Palace&lt;/b&gt; (Amer Fort) is a &lt;b&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/b&gt; and one of Rajasthan&#8217;s most magnificent forts. Perched on the Aravalli Hills above Maota Lake, this colossal palace-fort was built in &lt;b&gt;1592 AD by Raja Man Singh I&lt;/b&gt; and expanded by his successors over 150 years. The palace showcases &lt;b&gt;exquisite Rajput and Mughal architectural fusion&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; the Sheesh Mahal (Mirror Palace), Diwan-i-Aam, and Ganesh Pol gate with its brilliant frescoes are among India&#8217;s most breathtaking artistic achievements. Elephant rides and a spectacular Sound &amp; Light Show complete the experience.</string>
        <string name="td_amber_palace_tip_time_desc">Arrive at sunrise (7&#8211;8 AM) for a golden facade and the fewest crowds. The Maota Lake below mirrors the palace in stillness. Elephant rides begin at 7 AM &#8212; book in advance.</string>
        <string name="td_amber_palace_tip_season_desc">October to March offers perfect cool weather. The annual Elephant Festival (Holi season) at Amber is spectacular. Monsoon brings dramatic misty views but the climb can be wet.</string>
        <string name="td_amber_palace_tip_photo_desc">From the Maota Lake viewpoint below, the palace reflecting in the water is iconic. Inside, the Sheesh Mahal with thousands of tiny mirrors creates an otherworldly photography opportunity.</string>
        <string name="td_amber_palace_tip_wear_desc">Good walking shoes for the steep cobblestone approach path. Dress modestly &#8212; inner chambers of the palace have religious significance. Photo permits required for tripods (&#8377;200).</string>
        <string name="td_amber_palace_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;100 for Indian nationals and &#8377;500 for foreign nationals. Sound &amp; Light Show tickets are &#8377;295 (Hindi) / &#8377;395 (English). Open daily 8 AM &#8211; 5:30 PM; Light show 7&#8211;9 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ COLVA BEACH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_colva_beach_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Colva Beach&lt;/b&gt; is one of South Goa&#8217;s most beloved and expansive stretches of shoreline &#8212; a sweeping &lt;b&gt;25 km crescent of white sand&lt;/b&gt; lapped by the warm Arabian Sea. Far more serene than its northern counterparts, Colva attracts travellers seeking &lt;b&gt;peaceful sunsets, fresh seafood&lt;/b&gt;, and authentic Goan village life. The beach is famous for its gentle waves suitable for swimming, its traditional fishing community, and the miraculous &lt;b&gt;Menino Jesus statue&lt;/b&gt; in the nearby Our Lady of Mercy Church &#8212; drawing thousands of pilgrims each October.</string>
        <string name="td_colva_beach_tip_time_desc">October to March offers the best beach weather &#8212; cool evenings and calm seas. Visit between 6&#8211;8 AM for a quiet sunrise walk or 5&#8211;7 PM for spectacular Arabian Sea sunsets when the sky turns crimson and gold.</string>
        <string name="td_colva_beach_tip_season_desc">November to February is peak season with pleasant 25&#8211;30&#176;C temperatures. Avoid June&#8211;September (monsoon) when rough seas make swimming dangerous, though the stormy sea atmosphere is dramatic.</string>
        <string name="td_colva_beach_tip_photo_desc">Capture the traditional wooden fishing boats (canoes) at dawn when the fishermen bring in their catch. Long-exposure sunset shots from the main beach jetty create spectacular silhouette compositions.</string>
        <string name="td_colva_beach_tip_wear_desc">Light beach clothing and sunscreen are essential. Carry a sarong for modesty when visiting the nearby church. Water shoes help with rocky entry points. Stay hydrated &#8212; beach shacks sell fresh coconut water.</string>
        <string name="td_colva_beach_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the beach is completely free. Beach shack sunbeds typically cost &#8377;100&#8211;200. Water sports (parasailing, jet-ski) range &#8377;500&#8211;1,500. Fresh seafood thalis at shacks start from &#8377;200.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ ANJUNA MARKET ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_anjuna_market_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Anjuna Flea Market&lt;/b&gt; is Goa&#8217;s most legendary bazaar &#8212; a vibrant, colourful open-air market that has been running every &lt;b&gt;Wednesday since the 1960s&lt;/b&gt; when it was started by hippies selling their belongings to fund onward travel. Today it draws &lt;b&gt;thousands of visitors&lt;/b&gt; each week to browse Rajasthani and Tibetan handicrafts, Kashmiri spices, vintage clothing, beachwear, silver jewellery, and psychedelic art. Set against the backdrop of &lt;b&gt;North Goa&#8217;s rugged coastline&lt;/b&gt;, it is as much a cultural experience as a shopping destination.</string>
        <string name="td_anjuna_market_tip_time_desc">Arrive early (9&#8211;11 AM) to get the best bargains before the afternoon crowds arrive. The market winds down by sunset (6 PM). Wednesdays only &#8212; plan your Goa trip around this when in North Goa.</string>
        <string name="td_anjuna_market_tip_season_desc">November to February is the best time &#8212; the market is in full swing during peak tourist season. During monsoon (June&#8211;Sep) the market is closed. October sees the market restart for the season.</string>
        <string name="td_anjuna_market_tip_photo_desc">Arrive early for shots of stalls being set up &#8212; vendors arranging colourful goods create vibrant compositions. The coconut palm canopy overhead filters light beautifully for candid portraits of artisans at work.</string>
        <string name="td_anjuna_market_tip_wear_desc">Comfortable walking shoes are a must as the market is spread over a large area of uneven rocky ground. Carry cash (most vendors don&#8217;t accept cards). Bring a tote bag for purchases &#8212; plastic bags are limited.</string>
        <string name="td_anjuna_market_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the Anjuna Flea Market is completely free. Bargaining is expected and welcomed &#8212; vendors typically start 40&#8211;50% above their final price. Most items are priced &#8377;100&#8211;3,000.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ BASILICA OF BOM JESUS ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_basilica_bom_jesus_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Basilica of Bom Jesus&lt;/b&gt; (Good Jesus) is one of the finest examples of &lt;b&gt;Baroque architecture in Asia&lt;/b&gt; and a &lt;b&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/b&gt; since 1986. Built between &lt;b&gt;1594&#8211;1605 AD&lt;/b&gt; by the Portuguese Jesuits, it houses the &lt;b&gt;mortal remains of St. Francis Xavier&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; patron saint of Goa &#8212; in an ornate silver casket gifted by the Medici Duke of Tuscany. The saint&#8217;s body has been remarkably preserved for over 400 years and is displayed every ten years. The gilded altars, rich wood carvings, and sacred art within make this Goa&#8217;s most revered spiritual site.</string>
        <string name="td_basilica_bom_jesus_tip_time_desc">Visit between 9&#8211;11 AM or 3&#8211;5 PM to avoid the midday heat. Morning light falls beautifully on the laterite facade. Avoid visiting during Sunday Mass (8&#8211;11 AM) when the church is packed with worshippers.</string>
        <string name="td_basilica_bom_jesus_tip_season_desc">November to February is ideal. The Feast of St. Francis Xavier (December 3) sees massive pilgrimages and is a once-in-a-career cultural experience &#8212; book accommodation well in advance if you plan to attend.</string>
        <string name="td_basilica_bom_jesus_tip_photo_desc">The ornate facade is best photographed at golden hour when the laterite stone glows warm amber. Inside, the gilded main altar with its golden Infant Jesus statue makes for a powerful composition with wide-angle lens.</string>
        <string name="td_basilica_bom_jesus_tip_wear_desc">Modest dress is mandatory &#8212; shoulders and knees must be covered. Scarves are available at the entrance. Shoes must be removed. Photography is allowed in most areas but restricted near the sacred tomb chamber.</string>
        <string name="td_basilica_bom_jesus_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the Basilica is free. The adjacent Museum of Christian Art charges &#8377;5 for Indians and &#8377;100 for foreigners. Open Mon&#8211;Sat 9 AM&#8211;6:30 PM, Sun 10 AM&#8211;6:30 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ FONTAINHAS ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_fontainhas_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Fontainhas&lt;/b&gt; is Goa&#8217;s most charming heritage neighbourhood &#8212; a living &lt;b&gt;Latin Quarter of Panaji&lt;/b&gt; that transports visitors to 19th-century Portuguese colonial Goa. Narrow cobblestone lanes wind between &lt;b&gt;centuries-old mansions&lt;/b&gt; painted in vivid terracotta, ochre, mint, and azure, adorned with wrought iron balconies dripping with bougainvillea. Designated a &lt;b&gt;Heritage Zone by the Goa government&lt;/b&gt;, Fontainhas is home to historic chapels, the Altinho Hill viewpoint, traditional Goan Catholic families, and the city&#8217;s oldest bakeries &#8212; a true open-air museum of Indo-Portuguese culture.</string>
        <string name="td_fontainhas_tip_time_desc">Visit early morning (7&#8211;9 AM) when the streets are quiet and light falls softly on the coloured facades &#8212; magical for photography. Evenings (5&#8211;7 PM) when residents sit on their balconies are equally atmospheric.</string>
        <string name="td_fontainhas_tip_season_desc">November to March is perfect &#8212; cool and dry. The area is most colourful post-monsoon (Oct&#8211;Nov) when freshly repainted facades are vibrant. The Panjim Carnival (February) brings the quarter alive with parades.</string>
        <string name="td_fontainhas_tip_photo_desc">31st January Road is the most photographed lane &#8212; the cluster of painted houses with Chapel of St. Sebastian creates the quintessential Fontainhas composition. Use a 35mm lens for the intimate street scale.</string>
        <string name="td_fontainhas_tip_wear_desc">Comfortable walking shoes are essential for the uneven cobblestones and Altinho Hill climb. Dress modestly near chapels. Carry a small bottle of water &#8212; the area has few shops. A light jacket for cool evenings.</string>
        <string name="td_fontainhas_tip_tickets_desc">Exploring Fontainhas is completely free. Guided heritage walks (&#8377;500&#8211;800 per person) offer the best insight into the quarter&#8217;s history and architecture. The bakeries offer traditional Goan &#8377;10 bread (poi) worth trying.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ DUDHSAGAR FALLS ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_dudhsagar_falls_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Dudhsagar Falls&lt;/b&gt; (&#8216;Sea of Milk&#8217;) is one of India&#8217;s tallest and most spectacular waterfalls, plunging an astonishing &lt;b&gt;310 metres (1,017 feet)&lt;/b&gt; across four cascades from the Mandovi River on the Goa-Karnataka border. Nestled deep within the &lt;b&gt;Bhagwan Mahaveer Wildlife Sanctuary&lt;/b&gt;, the milky-white torrent of water crashing into a jade-green pool creates a breathtaking spectacle &#8212; especially during monsoon. The falls are accessible only via a thrilling &lt;b&gt;forest jeep safari&lt;/b&gt; through the Mollem National Park, passing through dense tropical jungle teeming with wildlife.</string>
        <string name="td_dudhsagar_falls_tip_time_desc">October to January offers the best combination &#8212; the falls are still full from monsoon but the jeep trail is accessible. At peak monsoon (July&#8211;Aug), the falls are most dramatic but access is restricted due to flooding.</string>
        <string name="td_dudhsagar_falls_tip_season_desc">October to March is the ideal visit window. The falls reduce significantly by April&#8211;May. Monsoon (June&#8211;Sep) sees the most powerful flow but jeep access is often closed &#8212; only experienced trekkers can reach on foot.</string>
        <string name="td_dudhsagar_falls_tip_photo_desc">From the jeep stop viewpoint, use a wide-angle lens to capture all four cascades in one shot. Morning visits (9&#8211;11 AM) have the best light. A neutral density filter reduces glare on the white water for dramatic long-exposure shots.</string>
        <string name="td_dudhsagar_falls_tip_wear_desc">Wear clothes you don&#8217;t mind getting wet &#8212; the mist near the falls is pervasive. Sports sandals or old shoes are better than sneakers (they will get soaked). Carry a waterproof bag for electronics and camera gear.</string>
        <string name="td_dudhsagar_falls_tip_tickets_desc">The Forest Department jeep safari package is approximately &#8377;400&#8211;500 per person (includes entry, jeep ride, and guide). Book through official Forest Department counters at Mollem. Open Oct&#8211;May; closed during monsoon.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ BAGA BEACH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_baga_beach_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Baga Beach&lt;/b&gt; is North Goa&#8217;s most vibrant and energetic coastal destination &#8212; a one-kilometre stretch of golden sand at the mouth of the &lt;b&gt;Baga River&lt;/b&gt; that has become synonymous with &lt;b&gt;Goa&#8217;s legendary nightlife&lt;/b&gt;. Home to legendary beach clubs (Tito&#8217;s, Cavala, Café Mambo), water sports, and some of Goa&#8217;s best seafood restaurants, Baga buzzes with energy from dawn to dawn. The &lt;b&gt;Baga River estuary&lt;/b&gt; provides a calm swimming area ideal for families, while the open sea end is perfect for parasailing, banana boat rides, and jet-skiing &#8212; making Baga the ultimate all-in-one Goa beach experience.</string>
        <string name="td_baga_beach_tip_time_desc">Early morning (6&#8211;8 AM) for a peaceful walk and sunrise. Late afternoon (4&#8211;7 PM) for water sports and sunset watching from a beach shack. Nightlife begins at 9 PM and runs till dawn at the clubs on Tito&#8217;s Lane.</string>
        <string name="td_baga_beach_tip_season_desc">November to February is peak season &#8212; the beach is buzzing but can get crowded. December&#8211;January (Christmas and New Year) sees huge beach parties. Monsoon (June&#8211;Sep) is off-season with rough seas but atmospheric empty streets.</string>
        <string name="td_baga_beach_tip_photo_desc">Capture the famous &#8216;Baga Sunsets&#8217; at the river mouth where the Baga River meets the sea &#8212; the reflection of the sky in the shallow river water is extraordinary. Drone views of the crescent bay are stunning.</string>
        <string name="td_baga_beach_tip_wear_desc">Beach-appropriate clothing for the daytime. Smart casual for evening restaurants and cafes. Most clubs have dress codes (no flip flops after 9 PM). Always carry sunscreen &#8212; the North Goa sun is intense year-round.</string>
        <string name="td_baga_beach_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to Baga Beach is free. Sun loungers cost &#8377;100&#8211;200 per day. Water sports packages range &#8377;500&#8211;2,000. Club entry fees range &#8377;500&#8211;1,500 on weekends (usually includes one drink). Fresh King Prawn curry from &#8377;400.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ PALOLEM BEACH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_palolem_beach_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Palolem Beach&lt;/b&gt; is widely considered South Goa&#8217;s most beautiful beach &#8212; a &lt;b&gt;crescent-shaped bay of powder-white sand&lt;/b&gt; sheltered by two wooded headlands, framing the turquoise Arabian Sea in a near-perfect arc. Far more tranquil and unspoiled than North Goa&#8217;s beaches, Palolem attracts those seeking &lt;b&gt;yoga retreats, dolphin spotting, sea kayaking&lt;/b&gt;, and candlelit beach-hut dinners. The sheltered bay creates exceptionally calm waters perfect for swimming. Since private construction is banned, accommodation consists entirely of &lt;b&gt;environmentally friendly bamboo beach huts&lt;/b&gt; set just behind the treeline.</string>
        <string name="td_palolem_beach_tip_time_desc">Sunrise (6&#8211;7 AM) at Palolem is extraordinary &#8212; dolphins are often spotted just offshore in the morning calm. Sunset from Honeymoon Point headland on the south end offers panoramic golden hour views of the entire bay.</string>
        <string name="td_palolem_beach_tip_season_desc">November to March is ideal &#8212; calm seas, perfect for kayaking and swimming. The famous &#8216;Silent Noise&#8217; headphone DJ parties run on weekends in season. Avoid June&#8211;September when the beach huts are dismantled for monsoon.</string>
        <string name="td_palolem_beach_tip_photo_desc">The full crescent bay is best photographed from the Honeymoon Point rocks at the south end of the beach. Aerial/elevated shots reveal the perfectly curved bay. Kayaking trips give unique sea-level perspectives looking back at the shore.</string>
        <string name="td_palolem_beach_tip_wear_desc">Palolem is very laid-back &#8212; beach casual is the norm all day and evening. Walk barefoot on the sand (it stays cool). Carry reef-safe sunscreen to protect the bay&#8217;s marine ecosystem. Bring a hammock for the palm grove.</string>
        <string name="td_palolem_beach_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is free. Kayak rental costs &#8377;300&#8211;500 per hour. Dolphin watching boat trips are &#8377;300&#8211;500 per person. Beach hut accommodation starts from &#8377;800 per night in season. Fresh catch beach BBQ from &#8377;500.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ AGONDA BEACH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_agonda_beach_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Agonda Beach&lt;/b&gt; is South Goa&#8217;s best-kept secret &#8212; a &lt;b&gt;3 km pristine, unspoiled crescent of ivory sand&lt;/b&gt; that has deliberately chosen to remain free from commercialisation. Nestled between green hills and gentle Arabian Sea surf, Agonda is one of the few Goa beaches where &lt;b&gt;Olive Ridley sea turtles&lt;/b&gt; come ashore to nest (November&#8211;February). The beach has no jet-skis, no parasailing, and no loud music &#8212; only authentic beach huts, yoga shalas, vegan cafés, and the soul-restoring sound of waves. Listed among India&#8217;s &lt;b&gt;cleanest and most peaceful beaches&lt;/b&gt;, Agonda is the antidote to Goa&#8217;s tourist overwhelm.</string>
        <string name="td_agonda_beach_tip_time_desc">Early morning (6&#8211;8 AM) is magical &#8212; turtles may be spotted laying eggs or returning to sea (Nov&#8211;Feb). The beach is empty and the light is golden. Sunset from the hilltop trail above the south end is extraordinarily peaceful.</string>
        <string name="td_agonda_beach_tip_season_desc">November to April is perfect. December&#8211;February is turtle nesting season &#8212; a wildlife experience found at very few Indian beaches. The beach huts open from October and close in June for monsoon. Monsoon Agonda is eerie and beautiful.</string>
        <string name="td_agonda_beach_tip_photo_desc">The long empty beach at low tide provides a perfect mirror reflection of the sky. Photograph along the waterline at sunrise heading north toward the headland. If you find turtle tracks at dawn, photograph respectfully from a distance.</string>
        <string name="td_agonda_beach_tip_wear_desc">Agonda is very relaxed &#8212; sarongs, beach dresses, and bare feet. Yoga clothing is widely worn all day. Carry insect repellent for evenings. Do not use bright lights or flash photography near turtle nesting zones &#8212; it disorients them.</string>
        <string name="td_agonda_beach_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to Agonda Beach is completely free. Beach hut accommodation starts from &#8377;600 per night. The beach has no water sports for hire &#8212; by community choice. Fresh catch fishing village meals from &#8377;250. Yoga sessions from &#8377;400.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ KASHI VISHWANATH TEMPLE ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_kashi_vishwanath_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Shri Kashi Vishwanath Temple&lt;/b&gt; is one of the most sacred Hindu temples in the world &#8212; the supreme abode of &lt;b&gt;Lord Shiva&lt;/b&gt;, situated on the western bank of the Holy Ganges in Varanasi. One of the twelve &lt;b&gt;Jyotirlingas&lt;/b&gt; (sacred Shiva shrines), the current temple was built in &lt;b&gt;1780 AD&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;b&gt;Ahilya Bai Holkar&lt;/b&gt; of Indore, with the &lt;b&gt;gold-plated spires&lt;/b&gt; (donated by Maharaja Ranjit Singh in 1835) soaring above the ancient city skyline. The &lt;b&gt;Kashi Vishwanath Corridor&lt;/b&gt;, inaugurated in 2022, has transformed the temple complex into a grand spiritual precinct connecting the sanctum directly to the Ganga ghats.</string>
        <string name="td_kashi_vishwanath_tip_time_desc">The temple opens at 3 AM for Mangala Aarti and closes at 11 PM. The &lt;b&gt;Shringar Aarti at 9 PM&lt;/b&gt; is the most serene experience. Visit on Mondays (Shiva&#8217;s sacred day) for the most spiritually charged atmosphere &#8212; but expect massive crowds.</string>
        <string name="td_kashi_vishwanath_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal &#8212; cool and pleasant. &lt;b&gt;Maha Shivaratri&lt;/b&gt; (Feb&#8211;Mar) sees the grandest celebrations with overnight puja and aarti. Shravan month (July&#8211;Aug) is the holiest but extremely crowded.</string>
        <string name="td_kashi_vishwanath_tip_photo_desc">Non-Hindus cannot enter the inner sanctum but can view the gold spires from the Gyanvapi area and the new corridor. Photography is restricted within temple premises &#8212; capture the golden spires at sunrise from across the lane for the best composition.</string>
        <string name="td_kashi_vishwanath_tip_wear_desc">Modest dress is mandatory &#8212; full sleeves and covered legs for all. Shoes must be removed and deposited at the entrance (lockers available). Women must cover their head. Avoid carrying large bags as security screening is strict.</string>
        <string name="td_kashi_vishwanath_tip_tickets_desc">Entry for Hindu devotees is free. The Kashi Vishwanath Corridor entry is free for all. Mobile phones and cameras are not permitted inside. VIP darshan queues are available for a nominal fee at specific counters. Open 3 AM &#8211; 11 PM daily.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ DASHASHWAMEDHA GHAT ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_dashashwamedha_ghat_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Dashashwamedha Ghat&lt;/b&gt; is Varanasi&#8217;s most magnificent and spiritually significant ghat &#8212; the main ghat on the Ganges where the &lt;b&gt;legendary Ganga Aarti&lt;/b&gt; is performed every evening by a group of priests using &lt;b&gt;massive fire torches&lt;/b&gt;, incense, conch shells, yak-tail fans, and sacred chants. According to Hindu mythology, Lord &lt;b&gt;Brahma created this ghat&lt;/b&gt; to welcome Lord Shiva after releasing the sacred Dashaswamedha Yagna (sacrifice of ten horses). As the spiritual heart of Varanasi, the ghat is a convergence of &lt;b&gt;ancient rituals, devotional music, flower offerings, and the eternal flame&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; creating one of India&#8217;s most unforgettable spectacles.</string>
        <string name="td_dashashwamedha_ghat_tip_time_desc">The &lt;b&gt;Ganga Aarti at sunset (6&#8211;7 PM in winter / 7&#8211;8 PM in summer)&lt;/b&gt; is the crown jewel of Varanasi. Arrive 45 minutes early to secure a spot. Early morning (5&#8211;7 AM) boat rides offer the magical blue-hour mist over the river with pilgrims bathing.</string>
        <string name="td_dashashwamedha_ghat_tip_season_desc">October to March is perfect &#8212; the cool mist on the Ganges at sunrise and the crisp evenings at aarti time are extraordinary. &lt;b&gt;Dev Deepawali&lt;/b&gt; (November &#8212; Kartik Purnima) when 84 ghats are lit with a million diyas is Varanasi&#8217;s most spectacular night.</string>
        <string name="td_dashashwamedha_ghat_tip_photo_desc">Photograph the Ganga Aarti from a boat on the river for the best perspective &#8212; the priests with the fire torches reflected in the dark water is extraordinarily dramatic. Rent a boat for &#8377;200&#8211;500 per person. Use a fast lens (f/1.8) for the low-light flame shots.</string>
        <string name="td_dashashwamedha_ghat_tip_wear_desc">Comfortable modest clothing for the ghat. Remove shoes when approaching the main aarti platform area. Evening can be cold (Nov&#8211;Feb) &#8212; carry a shawl. Beware of persistent boat touts &#8212; negotiate firmly before boarding. Carry a plastic bag to protect shoes.</string>
        <string name="td_dashashwamedha_ghat_tip_tickets_desc">The ghat is completely free to access. Boat rides cost &#8377;200&#8211;500 per person (negotiate firmly). Flower diyas (&#8377;20&#8211;50) are offered into the river as devotion. The aarti itself is free to watch from the steps or by boat. Open sunrise to midnight.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ ASSI GHAT ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_assi_ghat_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Assi Ghat&lt;/b&gt; is the southernmost and most bohemian of Varanasi&#8217;s 84 major ghats &#8212; a beloved gathering place where the &lt;b&gt;Assi River meets the sacred Ganges&lt;/b&gt;. Unlike the bustling Dashashwamedha Ghat, Assi Ghat has a more &lt;b&gt;laid-back, intellectual atmosphere&lt;/b&gt;, historically associated with Sanskrit scholars, sadhus, yoga practitioners, and the Banaras Hindu University community. The large &lt;b&gt;Peepal tree at the ghat&#8217;s end&lt;/b&gt; shelters a revered Shiva lingam. The ghat is also the venue for Varanasi&#8217;s famous &lt;b&gt;dawn Subah-e-Banaras cultural programme&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; a daily sunrise ritual of classical music, yoga, and devotional recitations that captures the soul of the ancient city.</string>
        <string name="td_assi_ghat_tip_time_desc">Sunrise (5&#8211;7 AM) is transformative &#8212; the &lt;b&gt;Subah-e-Banaras programme&lt;/b&gt; with classical musicians performing as the mist rises off the Ganges is unmissable. Evening (5&#8211;7 PM) is peaceful for watching the smaller, intimate aarti and sunset from the ghat steps.</string>
        <string name="td_assi_ghat_tip_season_desc">November to February is best &#8212; mornings are cool and misty. The ghat is at its most cultural and alive during the festival season. The nearby BHU campus vicinity makes it vibrant year-round with students and scholars unlike other ghats.</string>
        <string name="td_assi_ghat_tip_photo_desc">The magnificent river view looking north from Assi Ghat shows the string of 84 ghats stretching to the horizon &#8212; breathtaking at golden hour. At sunrise, silhouettes of bathers, yoga practitioners, and boats on the misty river make for extraordinary portrait photography.</string>
        <string name="td_assi_ghat_tip_wear_desc">Casual comfortable clothing appropriate for sitting on ghat steps. Remove shoes when close to the Peepal tree shrine. The ghat is more relaxed than central Varanasi ghats &#8212; yoga clothing is appropriate early morning. Carry mosquito repellent for dusk.</string>
        <string name="td_assi_ghat_tip_tickets_desc">Assi Ghat is completely free to access. Boat rides from Assi upstream to Dashashwamedha cost &#8377;300&#8211;600 per person (negotiate). The Subah-e-Banaras programme is free to attend. Tea from the chai stalls on the steps costs just &#8377;10 &#8212; the best seats in the city.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ RAMNAGAR FORT ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_ramnagar_fort_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Ramnagar Fort&lt;/b&gt; is an 18th-century sandstone palace-fort that has been the residence of the &lt;b&gt;Maharajas of Varanasi&lt;/b&gt; since 1750 AD. Situated directly across the Ganges from the main ghats, the fort&#8217;s &lt;b&gt;Mughal and Indian baroque architecture&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; with its towers, turrets, and pillared halls &#8212; reflects magnificently in the river. The fort houses a remarkable &lt;b&gt;museum&lt;/b&gt; with royal antiques: vintage American cars, ivory palanquins, a &lt;b&gt;17th-century astronomical clock&lt;/b&gt;, antique weapons, costumes, and wildlife trophies from the Maharaja&#8217;s hunting expeditions. The fort is also the headquarters for &lt;b&gt;Ramnagar Ramlila&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; the world&#8217;s largest theatrical performance, running 31 days every October.</string>
        <string name="td_ramnagar_fort_tip_time_desc">Visit between 10 AM and 5 PM (the museum hours). The best view of the fort is from a boat on the Ganges &#8212; the pale sandstone glowing in the afternoon sun is spectacular. October&#8211;November during the Ramlila season makes this the most lively and culturally rich visit.</string>
        <string name="td_ramnagar_fort_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal. &lt;b&gt;Ramnagar Ramlila (October)&lt;/b&gt; is a UNESCO-recognized tradition and one of India&#8217;s greatest living folk arts events &#8212; plan specially for this. The fort can be hot and dusty in summer months (April&#8211;June).</string>
        <string name="td_ramnagar_fort_tip_photo_desc">Photograph the fort from a boat on the Ganges at golden hour &#8212; the reflection in the water with the ancient sandstone walls makes a stunning composition. Inside, the vintage cars and the astronomical clock create unusual and fascinating detail shots.</string>
        <string name="td_ramnagar_fort_tip_wear_desc">Comfortable walking shoes for the uneven fort premises. Dress modestly &#8212; it is a living royal household with religious identity. Carry water as facilities inside the fort are limited. A guided tour is highly recommended to understand the museum&#8217;s collections fully.</string>
        <string name="td_ramnagar_fort_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the fort and museum: &#8377;15 for Indians, &#8377;25 for foreigners. A boat from Dashashwamedha Ghat to Ramnagar costs &#8377;300&#8211;500 return. Open 10 AM &#8211; 5 PM daily, closed on some festival days. Photography inside the museum is not permitted.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ TULSI MANAS MANDIR ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_tulsi_manas_mandir_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Shri Satyanarayan Tulsi Manas Mandir&lt;/b&gt; is one of Varanasi&#8217;s most distinctive temples &#8212; a modern white marble marvel built in &lt;b&gt;1964 AD&lt;/b&gt; on the exact site where the great saint-poet &lt;b&gt;Goswami Tulsidas wrote the Ramcharitmanas&lt;/b&gt; in the 16th century &#8212; his Hindi retelling of the Ramayana that transformed Indian spiritual and literary culture. The temple is dedicated to &lt;b&gt;Lord Ram, Sita, and Lakshman&lt;/b&gt;. What makes it extraordinary is that the entire &lt;b&gt;Ramcharitmanas text is engraved on the white marble walls&lt;/b&gt; of the temple &#8212; making it a sacred library in stone. Mechanical dioramas of Ramayana scenes in the basement delight visitors of all ages.</string>
        <string name="td_tulsi_manas_mandir_tip_time_desc">Open 5:30 AM to 12 PM and 3:30 PM to 9 PM. The evening aarti (7&#8211;8 PM) is very serene. Morning visits (6&#8211;8 AM) are peaceful for reading the Ramcharitmanas verses inscribed on the walls without the crowds of the afternoon.</string>
        <string name="td_tulsi_manas_mandir_tip_season_desc">October to March is perfect. &lt;b&gt;Ram Navami (March&#8211;April)&lt;/b&gt; sees spectacular celebrations at this temple. Being very close to Assi Ghat, combine both in a single day trip to the southern ghats for an efficient cultural itinerary.</string>
        <string name="td_tulsi_manas_mandir_tip_photo_desc">The white marble exterior with its intricate carvings is best photographed in morning light. Inside, close-up shots of the Ramcharitmanas text engraved in the walls with soft light filtering through lattice windows create beautifully spiritual compositions.</string>
        <string name="td_tulsi_manas_mandir_tip_wear_desc">Modest dress strictly required &#8212; shoulders and legs covered. Shoes must be removed at the entrance. The marble floors can be very hot in summer afternoons &#8212; carry socks. Non-Hindus are welcome inside the temple premises and inner sanctum.</string>
        <string name="td_tulsi_manas_mandir_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the temple is completely free. The Ramayana diorama exhibition in the basement has a nominal entry of &#8377;10. Open 5:30 AM&#8211;12 PM and 3:30&#8211;9 PM daily. Located just 500 metres from Assi Ghat &#8212; easily walkable. Photography permitted in the outer courtyard only.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ SARNATH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_sarnath_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Sarnath&lt;/b&gt; is one of the most sacred sites in Buddhism &#8212; the deer park where &lt;b&gt;Gautama Buddha gave his first sermon (Dhammacakkappavattana Sutta)&lt;/b&gt; after attaining enlightenment at Bodh Gaya, setting the &lt;b&gt;Wheel of Dharma in motion&lt;/b&gt;. Located just 13 km from Varanasi city centre, Sarnath is home to the magnificent &lt;b&gt;Dhamek Stupa (249 BC)&lt;/b&gt;, the &lt;b&gt;Lion Capital of Ashoka&lt;/b&gt; (India&#8217;s national emblem, discovered here), over a dozen international Buddhist temples from Tibet, Japan, China, Sri Lanka, and Myanmar, and the &lt;b&gt;Archaeological Museum&lt;/b&gt; housing priceless Buddhist antiquities. A serene oasis of extraordinary historical depth just minutes from the busy ghats.</string>
        <string name="td_sarnath_tip_time_desc">Open 9 AM to 5 PM daily. Visit in the morning (9&#8211;11 AM) when the light is soft and the complex is peaceful &#8212; Buddhist monks from the surrounding monasteries perform morning meditations in the Dhamek Stupa precinct. Allow at least 3 hours for the full site.</string>
        <string name="td_sarnath_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal &#8212; pleasant weather for exploring the large open archaeological park. &lt;b&gt;Buddha Purnima (April&#8211;May)&lt;/b&gt; is the most auspicious day with thousands of Buddhist pilgrims from across Asia in colourful robes &#8212; an extraordinary sight.</string>
        <string name="td_sarnath_tip_photo_desc">The Dhamek Stupa photographed with a wide-angle lens at golden hour (4&#8211;5 PM) against the blue sky is the signature Sarnath composition. The carved geometric and floral patterns on the stupa&#8217;s cylindrical surface make extraordinary close-up detail shots.</string>
        <string name="td_sarnath_tip_wear_desc">Dress modestly and remove shoes before entering the main Dhamek Stupa precinct area. The site is spread over a large area &#8212; comfortable walking shoes essential. Carry water. A good audio guide or local guide (&#8377;200&#8211;300) is invaluable for understanding the historical context.</string>
        <string name="td_sarnath_tip_tickets_desc">Sarnath archaeological site entry: &#8377;15 for Indians, &#8377;200 for foreigners. The Archaeological Museum charges separately: &#8377;5 for Indians, &#8377;100 for foreigners (closed Fridays). International Buddhist temples are free to enter. Open sunrise to sunset. Combined with Dhamek Stupa in one ticket.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ MANIKARNIKA GHAT ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_manikarnika_ghat_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Manikarnika Ghat&lt;/b&gt; is Varanasi&#8217;s most sacred and ancient cremation ghat &#8212; believed by Hindus to be the &lt;b&gt;holiest place to die and be cremated&lt;/b&gt;, as Lord Shiva himself whispers the &lt;b&gt;Taraka Mantra&lt;/b&gt; (liberation mantra) into the ear of each dying soul here, granting &lt;b&gt;moksha (liberation from the cycle of rebirth)&lt;/b&gt;. The &lt;b&gt;sacred fire that lights every funeral pyre&lt;/b&gt; has reportedly burned continuously for &lt;b&gt;over 3,500 years&lt;/b&gt;. Witnessing this ancient rite of passage &#8212; where humanity confronts mortality with extraordinary equanimity &#8212; is one of the most profound, humbling, and life-changing experiences in the world. The ghat operates 24 hours a day, 365 days a year.</string>
        <string name="td_manikarnika_ghat_tip_time_desc">The ghat burns through day and night without pause. Dawn (5&#8211;7 AM) is the most atmospheric &#8212; the smoke rises through the morning mist with a haunting quality. Evening visits can be powerful as the flames reflect on the river. Respect that this is an active, sacred space &#8212; never hurry.</string>
        <string name="td_manikarnika_ghat_tip_season_desc">Manikarnika is active year-round. October to March is the most comfortable weather for visiting. During &lt;b&gt;Makar Sankranti, Pitru Paksha, and Shivratri&lt;/b&gt;, the number of cremations dramatically increases as these are considered especially auspicious times for departure.</string>
        <string name="td_manikarnika_ghat_tip_photo_desc">Photography of the cremation ceremonies is strictly prohibited and deeply disrespectful &#8212; do not attempt this. The best approach is a boat on the Ganges at a respectful distance. The wider ghat area, the burning ghats&#8217; ancient structure, and the city skyline behind are appropriate subjects.</string>
        <string name="td_manikarnika_ghat_tip_wear_desc">Dress with deep solemnity and modesty &#8212; completely covered clothing is essential. Do not show any emotion that may be misinterpreted. Never point your feet toward a funeral pyre. Be wary of &#8216;guides&#8217; who demand large donations for the wood funds &#8212; politely decline all solicitations.</string>
        <string name="td_manikarnika_ghat_tip_tickets_desc">The ghat is completely free to approach and observe respectfully from the steps or a boat (&#8377;200&#8211;500). There is &lt;b&gt;no official fee&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; ignore anyone demanding money for standing there. The ghat is active 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. Approach with the utmost respect and humility.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ SNOW KINGDOM ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_snow_kingdom_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Snow Kingdom&lt;/b&gt; is South India&#8217;s largest indoor snow theme park, located inside the &lt;b&gt;Express Avenue Mall&lt;/b&gt; in Royapettah, Chennai. Maintained at a chilling &lt;b&gt;&#8722;5&#176;C&lt;/b&gt;, this 10,000 sq ft winter wonderland brings the experience of real snow to the tropical shores of the Bay of Bengal. Visitors can enjoy &lt;b&gt;snow slides, snowball fights, ice sculptures, an igloo zone&lt;/b&gt;, and life-sized snowman characters &#8212; all without leaving the city. Thermal suits, gloves, and boots are provided at entry, making it a &lt;b&gt;completely self-contained arctic adventure&lt;/b&gt; ideal for families and children.</string>
        <string name="td_snow_kingdom_tip_time_desc">Visit on weekday mornings (10 AM&#8211;12 PM) when crowds are thinnest. Weekends can be very busy with families, especially during school holidays. Allow at least 1.5&#8211;2 hours inside for the full experience.</string>
        <string name="td_snow_kingdom_tip_wear_desc">Thermal coats, gloves, and snow boots are provided at the entry counter and included in the ticket price. Wear a full-sleeve inner layer and socks for extra warmth &#8212; it is genuinely cold at &#8722;5&#176;C. Avoid wearing sandals underneath the boots.</string>
        <string name="td_snow_kingdom_tip_photo_desc">The ice sculptures and illuminated snow zones are the best photo spots. Bring a waterproof camera or phone case &#8212; condensation forms quickly when electronics move from the cold zone to the warm mall air. Action shots on the snow slides are great with burst mode.</string>
        <string name="td_snow_kingdom_tip_tickets_desc">Entry is &#8377;450&#8211;650 per person depending on the package. Book tickets online or at Express Avenue Mall to avoid queues. Open daily 10 AM&#8211;9 PM. Children under 2 years may enter free. The experience lasts approximately 45&#8211;90 minutes.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ KAPALEESHWARAR TEMPLE ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_kapaleeshwarar_temple_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Shri Kapaleeshwarar Temple&lt;/b&gt; in Mylapore is Chennai&#8217;s most magnificent Dravidian temple &#8212; a supreme example of Tamil Nadu&#8217;s &lt;b&gt;Dravidian architectural style&lt;/b&gt; dating to the &lt;b&gt;7th century CE&lt;/b&gt;. Dedicated to &lt;b&gt;Lord Shiva (Kapaleeshwarar)&lt;/b&gt; and his consort Goddess Karpagambal, the temple&#8217;s soaring &lt;b&gt;37-metre gopuram (gateway tower)&lt;/b&gt; is adorned with thousands of painted stucco sculptures of Hindu deities. According to legend, the original temple was built on the seashore but was destroyed by the Portuguese and rebuilt in its current location in the 16th century. The temple&#8217;s sacred Karpaga Tank and the adjacent bustling Mylapore neighbourhood make this one of Chennai&#8217;s most spiritually and culturally vibrant destinations.</string>
        <string name="td_kapaleeshwarar_temple_tip_time_desc">Visit during puja timings &#8212; 5:30&#8211;6:30 AM (Thiruvanandal) or 6&#8211;7 PM (Sandhyakaalam) &#8212; for the most devotional atmosphere with lit oil lamps, incense, and chanting. The temple is very crowded on Fridays, Pradosham days, and during Brahmotsavam festival (March&#8211;April).</string>
        <string name="td_kapaleeshwarar_temple_tip_season_desc">Open year-round. The Arubathimoovar Festival (March&#8211;April) is the grandest &#8212; 63 Nayanmars (Tamil Saints) statues are ceremonially taken in procession through Mylapore&#8217;s streets. A spectacular sight unique to this temple.</string>
        <string name="td_kapaleeshwarar_temple_tip_wear_desc">Traditional modest dress is required &#8212; men must remove shirts inside the inner sanctum (dhoti or lungi is ideal) and women must wear saree or salwar. Remove footwear at the entrance. Non-Hindus may enter the outer corridors but access to the main sanctum may be restricted during puja times.</string>
        <string name="td_kapaleeshwarar_temple_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the temple is free for all. Special darshan tickets may be available for festivals. Open 5:30 AM&#8211;12 PM and 4 PM&#8211;9 PM daily. The temple tank and surrounding area are accessible throughout the day. Photography is restricted inside the main sanctum.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ MARINA BEACH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_marina_beach_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Marina Beach&lt;/b&gt; is the world&#8217;s &lt;b&gt;second longest urban beach&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; an unbroken 13 km crescent of golden sand stretching along Chennai&#8217;s eastern coastline. Facing the Bay of Bengal, Marina has been the heart of Chennai&#8217;s public life for over 150 years. The beach promenade is lined with &lt;b&gt;statues of Tamil icons&lt;/b&gt;: Mahatma Gandhi, former Chief Ministers, and Thiruvalluvar. Food stalls serving &lt;b&gt;sundal, bhajias, murukku, and fresh corn&lt;/b&gt; create a festive atmosphere at dusk. While swimming is &lt;b&gt;not recommended&lt;/b&gt; due to strong currents and rip tides, the sunrise views, the evening sea breeze, and the sheer scale of this magnificent urban shoreline make Marina one of India&#8217;s most beloved public spaces visited by &lt;b&gt;thousands daily&lt;/b&gt;.</string>
        <string name="td_marina_beach_tip_time_desc">Sunrise (5:30&#8211;7 AM) is the most magical time &#8212; the sky turns shades of orange and pink above the Bay of Bengal and the beach is populated with morning walkers and fishermen. Evening (5&#8211;7 PM) is when the entire city gathers for the sea breeze &#8212; energetic and vibrant.</string>
        <string name="td_marina_beach_tip_season_desc">November to February offers the most pleasant weather &#8212; cool evenings and calm mornings. Avoid peak summer (April&#8211;June) when the sand becomes scorchingly hot. Post-monsoon (October&#8211;November) brings big waves and a dramatic sea.</string>
        <string name="td_marina_beach_tip_photo_desc">Photograph the long shoreline looking north at sunrise from the Fort St. George end for a sweeping panoramic composition. The silhouettes of fishermen pulling in their traditional catamarans (wooden rafts) at dawn are iconic and deeply photogenic subjects.</string>
        <string name="td_marina_beach_tip_safety_desc">Do NOT swim at Marina Beach &#8212; the currents are dangerously strong and rip tides are common. Beach lifeguards are present but swimming is officially prohibited. Keep children away from the waterline. Secure your belongings in crowds during festivals.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ PARTHASARATHY TEMPLE ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_parthasarathy_temple_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Arulmigu Thiruvallikeni Parthasarathy Temple&lt;/b&gt; in Triplicane is one of the 108 Divya Desams &#8212; the most sacred temples of &lt;b&gt;Lord Vishnu&lt;/b&gt; in Vaishnavism. Built originally by the &lt;b&gt;Pallava kings in the 8th century CE&lt;/b&gt; and later expanded by the Vijayanagara emperors, this magnificent Dravidian temple is unique in housing &lt;b&gt;five forms of Lord Vishnu&lt;/b&gt;: Parthasarathy (the charioteer &#8212; a form never seen elsewhere with his bow and arrows), Rama, Narasimha, Trivikrama, and Gajendra Varadha. The presiding deity &lt;b&gt;Parthasarathy (Lord Krishna as Arjuna&#8217;s charioteer in the Mahabharata)&lt;/b&gt; is depicted with battle scars &#8212; making this an extraordinarily rare and profound sacred image. The temple&#8217;s &lt;b&gt;Brahmotsavam festival&lt;/b&gt; draws lakhs of devotees annually.</string>
        <string name="td_parthasarathy_temple_tip_time_desc">Visit during morning puja (6&#8211;8 AM) or evening puja (6&#8211;8:30 PM) for the most devotional atmosphere with full rituals. Vaikunta Ekadashi (December&#8211;January) &#8212; when the Swarga Vaasal (Door to Heaven) is opened &#8212; sees thousands of devotees queuing through the night for the rare darshan.</string>
        <string name="td_parthasarathy_temple_tip_wear_desc">Men must wear traditional dhoti (lungi acceptable) inside the main sanctum &#8212; the temple strictly enforces this. Women must wear saree or full-length traditional attire. Remove footwear at the entrance. Dress materials are usually available for rent near the temple entrance for visitors unfamiliar with the dress code.</string>
        <string name="td_parthasarathy_temple_tip_season_desc">Open year-round. The Brahmotsavam festival (spanning 10 days, typically in March&#8211;April) is the grandest celebration with magnificent processions of the deity on different vahanas (vehicles) through the streets of Triplicane &#8212; a spectacular living tradition.</string>
        <string name="td_parthasarathy_temple_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to the temple is free. Special darshan tickets (archanai/abhishekam) are available at the ticket counter. Temple open 6 AM&#8211;12 PM and 4 PM&#8211;8:30 PM daily. Photography is strictly prohibited inside the main sanctum. The gopuram exterior may be photographed from outside.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ SAN THOME CHURCH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_san_thome_church_about_text">&lt;b&gt;San Thome Cathedral Basilica&lt;/b&gt; is one of only three churches in the world built over the tomb of one of the twelve apostles of Jesus Christ &#8212; &lt;b&gt;St. Thomas the Apostle (Doubting Thomas)&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; who is believed to have brought Christianity to India in &lt;b&gt;52 AD&lt;/b&gt; and was martyred at St. Thomas Mount in Chennai in 72 AD. Originally built by the &lt;b&gt;Portuguese in 1504 AD&lt;/b&gt; and rebuilt as a &lt;b&gt;neo-Gothic cathedral&lt;/b&gt; in 1896, the church was elevated to a &lt;b&gt;Minor Basilica by Pope John Paul II in 1956&lt;/b&gt;. Its gleaming white Gothic spire rises dramatically above the Bay of Bengal shoreline. The tomb of St. Thomas in the crypt below the main altar is a site of profound &lt;b&gt;Christian pilgrimage&lt;/b&gt; drawing believers from across the world throughout the year.</string>
        <string name="td_san_thome_church_tip_time_desc">Visit outside Sunday Mass times (6 AM, 7 AM, 8:30 AM, 6 PM) for a peaceful experience. Weekday mornings (9&#8211;11 AM) are the quietest. The Feast of St. Thomas (July 3) sees the most vibrant celebrations with processions and thousands of pilgrims. The church is beautifully lit in the evenings.</string>
        <string name="td_san_thome_church_tip_season_desc">Open year-round. Christmas Eve Midnight Mass and Easter services at San Thome are extraordinarily atmospheric events. July 3 (Feast of St. Thomas) is the most important date in the church&#8217;s calendar and draws large crowds of Christians from across Tamil Nadu.</string>
        <string name="td_san_thome_church_tip_wear_desc">Modest dress is mandatory inside the church &#8212; shoulders must be covered; women should bring a scarf or shawl. Remove headwear inside the church. Maintain silence and solemnity throughout the visit. Photography is generally permitted in the main nave but not during Mass services.</string>
        <string name="td_san_thome_church_tip_tickets_desc">Entry to San Thome Cathedral is completely free and open to visitors of all faiths. The church museum (small donation requested) displays relics and the history of St. Thomas&#8217; ministry in India. Open 6 AM&#8211;8 PM daily. The crypt containing the apostle&#8217;s tomb is accessible during visiting hours. The nearby beach adds to the beauty of the visit.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ ELLIOT'S BEACH ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_elliots_beach_about_text">&lt;b&gt;Edward Elliot&#8217;s Beach&lt;/b&gt; (known locally as &lt;b&gt;Besant Nagar Beach&lt;/b&gt; or simply &#8216;Bessie&#8217;) is Chennai&#8217;s most beloved, calm, and upscale beach &#8212; a refreshing contrast to the vast and busy Marina Beach. Nestled at the southern end of Chennai&#8217;s coastline in the &lt;b&gt;affluent Besant Nagar neighbourhood&lt;/b&gt;, Elliot&#8217;s Beach is a favourite haunt of Chennai&#8217;s young professionals, families, and evening walkers seeking the sea breeze in a more relaxed and intimate setting. The beach is lined with &lt;b&gt;popular restaurants, cafes, and bakeries&lt;/b&gt; along the promenade &#8212; Amethyst, Zara&#8217;s, and Luna Luna being iconic stops. The serene &lt;b&gt;Ashtalakshmi Temple&lt;/b&gt; at the southern end of the beach adds a spiritual dimension to one of the city&#8217;s most charming coastal retreats.</string>
        <string name="td_elliots_beach_tip_time_desc">Visit in the evening (5&#8211;7:30 PM) for the cooling sea breeze and golden sunset hour &#8212; this is when Chennai&#8217;s upscale crowd fills the promenade and the beach comes alive. Early morning (6&#8211;8 AM) is peaceful and great for a quiet walk. The beach feels very different &#8212; and special &#8212; in both moods.</string>
        <string name="td_elliots_beach_tip_season_desc">October to March is the most pleasant season. The promenade restaurants and cafes are lively year-round. During Pongal (January) and Karthigai Deepam (November&#8211;December), the Ashtalakshmi Temple at the beach end hosts special events and is beautifully decorated.</string>
        <string name="td_elliots_beach_tip_photo_desc">The Ashtalakshmi Temple photographed at dusk with the sea behind it creates one of Chennai&#8217;s most striking compositions. The evening scene along the promenade &#8212; couples, families, food stalls, and the lighthouse in the background &#8212; makes for wonderful candid street photography in warm evening light.</string>
        <string name="td_elliots_beach_tip_food_desc">The promenade behind Elliot&#8217;s Beach is one of Chennai&#8217;s best food strips &#8212; perfect for post-beach dining. Try the legendary sundal (spiced chickpeas) from beach cart vendors (&#8377;20), or head to Luna Luna for Mexican, Zara&#8217;s for Mediterranean, or Anjappar for authentic Chettinad cuisine. The area is particularly lively after 7 PM.</string>
    
        <!-- ══════════ DHAMEK STUPA ══════════ -->
        <string name="td_dhamek_stupa_about_text">The &lt;b&gt;Dhamek Stupa&lt;/b&gt; is the most prominent and magnificent monument at Sarnath &#8212; a massive cylindrical &lt;b&gt;Buddhist stupa standing 43.6 metres (143 ft) tall&lt;/b&gt; built by &lt;b&gt;Emperor Ashoka in 249 BC&lt;/b&gt; and later expanded in the Gupta period (5th&#8211;6th century AD). It marks the precise spot where &lt;b&gt;Lord Buddha gave his first sermon&lt;/b&gt; to his five disciples after attaining enlightenment, known as &lt;b&gt;Dhammacakkappavattana&lt;/b&gt; &#8212; &#8216;Turning of the Wheel of the Law.&#8217; The lower portion of the stupa is exquisitely decorated with &lt;b&gt;interlaced floral scrolls, birds, and human figures&lt;/b&gt; in the Gupta style &#8212; among the finest examples of ancient Indian stone carving. A UNESCO-nominated site of global Buddhist pilgrimage.</string>
        <string name="td_dhamek_stupa_tip_time_desc">Open 9 AM to 5 PM daily. Morning visits (9&#8211;11 AM) are most peaceful &#8212; Buddhist monks from various nationalities meditate around the stupa in silence. Visit on &lt;b&gt;Buddha Purnima&lt;/b&gt; (April&#8211;May) for the extraordinary sight of international pilgrims in colourful robes circumambulating the stupa in prayer.</string>
        <string name="td_dhamek_stupa_tip_season_desc">October to March is ideal. The stupa is within the same Archaeological Park as the main Sarnath ruins &#8212; your single entry ticket covers both. Plan at least half a day to properly explore Sarnath including the Dhamek Stupa, Ashoka Pillar ruins, Mulagandhakuti Vihara, and the museum.</string>
        <string name="td_dhamek_stupa_tip_photo_desc">Photograph the full stupa from the far end of the archaeological park lawn for the complete 43.6 m height. The afternoon sun (3&#8211;5 PM) illuminates the carved stone panels on the lower drum beautifully. Telephoto lens shots of the intricate Gupta-era carvings reveal extraordinary detail.</string>
        <string name="td_dhamek_stupa_tip_wear_desc">Remove shoes before entering the main Dhamek Stupa area &#8212; the surrounding lawn is considered sacred ground. Dress modestly. The stupa complex is within the larger Sarnath Archaeological Park which requires comfortable walking shoes. Carry water and a hat for sun protection.</string>
        <string name="td_dhamek_stupa_tip_tickets_desc">Entry covered under Sarnath Archaeological Park ticket: &#8377;15 for Indians, &#8377;200 for foreigners. The Archaeological Museum (with the Lion Capital of Ashoka) is a separate ticket: &#8377;5 / &#8377;100. Open 9 AM &#8211; 5 PM daily (Museum closed Fridays). Circumambulation of the stupa is free after entry.</string>
</resources>